Turn Your Curiosity Into Discovery

Latest Facts

Health Science

19 Dec 2024

Health Science

19 Dec 2024

Privacy Policy
==============

Facts.net (“we”, “us”, or “our”) respects the privacy of our users. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard your information when you visit our website, including any other media form, media channel, mobile website, or mobile application related or connected thereto (collectively, the “Site”). If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, or our practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us at **contact@facts.net**.

When you visit our website and use our services, you trust us with your personal information. We take your privacy very seriously. We seek to explain to you in the clearest way possible what information we collect, how we use it, and what rights you have in relation to it. This privacy policy applies to all information collected through our, and/or any related services, sales, marketing, or events. If there are any terms in this privacy policy that you do not agree with, please discontinue the use of our site and our services.

Please read this privacy policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with us.

Collection of Your Information
------------------------------

### Personal information you disclose to us

_We collect personal information that you provide to us such as name, address, contact information, passwords and security data, payment information, and social media login data._

We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when registering at the Site, expressing an interest in obtaining information about us or our products and services, when participating in activities on the Site (such as posting messages in our online forums or entering competitions, contests or giveaways) or otherwise contacting us.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and the Site, the choices you make and the products and features you use. The personal information we collect can include the following:

**Name and Contact Data.** We collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone [number](https://facts.net/number-facts/ "number"), and other similar contact data.

**Credentials.** We collect passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication and account access.

**Payment Data**. We collect data necessary to process your payment if you make purchases, such as your payment instrument number (such as a credit card number), and the security code associated with your payment instrument. All payment data is stored by our payment processor and you should review its privacy policies and contact the payment processor directly to respond to your questions.

**Social Media Login Data**. We provide you with the option to register using social media account details, like your Facebook, [Twitter](https://facts.net/twitter-facts/ "Twitter") or other social media account. If you choose to register in this way, we will collect the Information described in the section called “Social Logins” below.

All personal information that you provide to us must be true, complete and accurate, and you must notify us of any changes to such personal information.

### Information automatically collected

_Some information – such as IP address and/or browser and device characteristics – is collected automatically when you visit our websites._

We automatically collect certain information when you visit, use or navigate the Site. This information does not reveal your specific identity (like your name or contact information) but may include device and usage information, such as your IP address, browser and device characteristics, operating system, [language](https://facts.net/language-facts/ "language") preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when you use our Site and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of our Site, and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes.

Like many businesses, we also collect information through cookies and similar technologies.

### Information collected from other sources

_We may collect limited data from public databases, marketing partners, social media platforms, and other outside sources._

We may obtain information about you from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms (such as Facebook), as well as from other third parties. Examples of the information we receive from other sources include: social media profile information (your name, gender, [birthday](https://facts.net/birthday-facts/ "birthday"), email, current city, state and country, user identification numbers for your contacts, profile picture URL and any other information that you choose to make public); marketing leads and search results and links, including paid listings (such as sponsored links).

Use of Your Information
-----------------------

_We process your information for purposes based on legitimate business interests, the fulfillment of our contract with you, compliance with our legal obligations, and/or your consent._

We use personal information collected via our Site for a variety of business purposes described below. We process your personal information for these purposes in [reliance](https://facts.net/general/18-facts-about-reliance/ "reliance") on our legitimate business interests (“Business Purposes”), in order to enter into or perform a contract with you (“Contractual”), with your consent (“Consent”), and/or for compliance with our legal obligations (“Legal Reasons”). We indicate the specific processing grounds we rely on next to each purpose listed below.

We use the information we collect or receive:

**To send administrative information to you** for Business Purposes, Legal Reasons and/or possibly Contractual. We may use your personal information to send you product, service and new feature information and/or information about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.

**To post testimonials** with your Consent. We post testimonials on our Site that may contain personal information. Prior to posting a testimonial, we will obtain your consent to use your name and testimonial. If you wish to update, or delete your testimonial, please contact us at **contact@facts.net** and be sure to include your name, testimonial location, and contact information.

**To deliver targeted advertising to you** for our Business Purposes and/or with your Consent. We may use your information to develop and display content and advertising (and work with third parties who do so) tailored to your interests and/or location and to measure its effectiveness.

**To administer prize draws and competitions** for our Business Purposes and/or with your Consent. We may use your information to administer prize draws and competitions when you elect to participate in competitions.

**To request Feedback** for our Business Purposes and/or with your Consent. We may use your information to request feedback and to contact you about your use of our Site.

**To protect our Site** for Business Purposes and/or Legal Reasons. We may use your information as part of our efforts to keep our Site safe and secure (for example, for fraud monitoring and prevention).

**To enable user-to-user communications** with your consent. We may use your information in order to enable user-to-user communications with each user’s consent.

**To enforce our terms, conditions and policies** for Business Purposes, Legal Reasons and/or possibly Contractual.

**To respond to legal requests and prevent harm** for Legal Reasons. If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.

**For other Business Purposes**. We may use your information for other Business Purposes, such as data analysis, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and to evaluate and improve our Site, products, services, marketing and your experience.

Disclosure of Your Information
------------------------------

_We only share information with your consent, to comply with laws, to protect your rights, or to fulfill business obligations._

We only share and disclose your information in the following situations:

**Compliance with Laws**. We may disclose your information where we are legally required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).

**Vital Interests and Legal Rights**. We may disclose your information where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding potential violations of our policies, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person and illegal activities, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

**Vendors, Consultants and Other Third-Party Service Providers**. We may share your data with third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform services for us or on our behalf and require access to such information to do that work. Examples include: payment processing, data analysis, email delivery, hosting services, customer service and marketing efforts. We may allow selected third parties to use tracking [technology](https://facts.net/technology-facts/ "technology") on the Site, which will enable them to collect data about how you interact with the Site over time. This information may be used to, among other things, analyze and [track](https://facts.net/track-facts/ "track") data, determine the popularity of certain content and better understand online activity. Unless described in this Policy, we do not share, sell, rent or trade any of your information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

**Business Transfers**. We may share or transfer your information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.

**Third-Party Advertisers**. We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Site. These companies may use information about your visits to our Site and other websites that are contained in web cookies and other tracking technologies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

**Affiliates**. We may share your information with our affiliates, in which case we will require those affiliates to honor this privacy policy. Affiliates include our parent company and any subsidiaries, joint venture partners or other companies that we control or that are under [common](https://facts.net/celebrity/17-fascinating-facts-about-common/ "common") control with us.

**Business Partners**. We may share your information with our business partners to offer you certain products, services or promotions.

**With your Consent**. We may disclose your personal information for any other purpose with your consent.

**Other Users**. When you share personal information (for example, by posting comments, contributions or other content to the Site) or otherwise interact with public areas of the Site, such personal information may be viewed by all users and may be publicly distributed outside the Site in perpetuity. Similarly, other users will be able to view descriptions of your activity, communicate with you within our Site, and view your profile.

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies
---------------------------------------

_We may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect and store your information._

### Cookies

We may use cookies and similar tracking technologies (like web beacons and pixels) to access or store information.

### Internet-Based Advertising

We may use third-party software to serve ads on the Site, implement email marketing campaigns, and manage other interactive marketing initiatives. This third-party software may use cookies or similar tracking technology to help manage and optimize your online experience with us.

### Website Analytics

We may also partner with selected third-party vendors, such as [Google](https://facts.net/google-facts/ "Google") Analytics and others, to allow tracking technologies and remarketing services on the Site through the use of first-party cookies and third-party cookies, to, among other things, analyze and track users’ use of the Site, determine the popularity of certain content and better understand online activity. By accessing the Site, you consent to the collection and use of your information by these third-party vendors. You are encouraged to review their privacy policy and contact them directly for responses to your questions. We do not transfer personal information to these third-party vendors.

You should be aware that getting a new [computer](https://facts.net/computer-facts/ "computer"), installing a new browser, upgrading an existing browser, or erasing or otherwise altering your browser’s cookies files may also clear certain opt-out cookies, plug-ins, or settings.

Use of Google Maps
------------------

_We use Google Maps for the purpose of providing better service._

This website, mobile application, or Facebook application uses Google Maps APIs. You may find the Google Maps APIs Terms of Service [here](https://developers.google.com/maps/terms). To better understand Google’s Privacy Policy, please refer to this [link](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

By using our Maps API Implementation, you agree to be bound by Google’s [Terms of Service](https://facts.net/tech-and-sciences/7-facts-about-terms-of-service/ "Terms of Service"). By using our implementation of the Google Maps APIs, you agree to allow us to gain access to information about you including personally identifiable information (such as usernames) and non-personally identifiable information (such as location).

For a full list of what we use information for, please see the previous sections titled “Use of Your Information” and “Disclosure of Your Information.” You agree to allow us to obtain or cache your location. You may revoke your consent at anytime. We use information about location in conjunction with data from other data providers.

Handling of Your Social Logins
------------------------------

_If you choose to register or log in to our websites using a social media account, we may have access to certain information about you._

Our Site offers you the ability to register and login using your third-party social media account details (like your Facebook or Twitter logins). Where you choose to do this, we will receive certain profile information about you from your social media provider. The profile information we receive may vary depending on the social media provider concerned, but will often include your name, e-mail address, [friends](https://facts.net/friends-facts/ "friends") list, profile picture as well as other information you choose to make public. If you login using Facebook, we may also request access to other permissions related to your account, such as friends, check-ins, and likes, and you may choose to grant or deny us access to each individual permission.

We will use the information we receive only for the purposes that are described in this privacy policy or that are otherwise made clear to you on the Site. Please note that we do not control, and are not responsible for, other uses of your personal information by your third-party social media provider. We recommend that you review their privacy policy to understand how they collect, use and share your personal information, and how you can set your privacy preferences on their sites and apps.

Transfer of Information Internationally
---------------------------------------

_We may transfer, store, and process your information in countries other than your own._

Our servers are located in the [United](https://facts.net/airlines/17-facts-about-united/ "United") States. If you are accessing our Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed by us in our facilities and by those third parties with whom we may share your personal information (see “Disclosure of Your Information” above), in the United States and other countries.

If you are a resident in the European Economic Area, then these countries may not have data protection or other laws as comprehensive as those in your country. We will however take all necessary measures to protect your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable law.

**European Commission’s Standard Contractual:** Such measures implementing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information between our group companies and between us and our third-party providers, which require all such recipients to protect personal information that they process from the EEA in accordance with European data protection laws. We have implemented similar appropriate safeguards with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided upon request.

Third-Party Websites
--------------------

_We are not responsible for the safety of any information that you share with third-party providers who advertise, but are not affiliated with, our websites._

The Site may contain advertisements from third parties that are not affiliated with us and which may link to other websites, online services or mobile applications. We cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of data you provide to any third parties. Any data collected by third parties is not covered by this privacy policy. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of any third parties, including other websites, services or applications that may be linked to or from the Site. You should review the policies of such third parties and contact them directly to respond to your questions.

How Long Do We Keep Your Information?
-------------------------------------

_We keep your information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy unless otherwise required by law._

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). No purpose in this policy will require us keeping your personal information for longer than 2 years.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

Keeping Your Information Safe
-----------------------------

_We aim to protect your personal information through a system of organizational and technical security measures._

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, please also remember that we cannot guarantee that the [internet](https://facts.net/internet-facts/ "internet") itself is 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Site is at your own risk. You should only access the services within a secure [environment](https://facts.net/nature/universe/19-facts-about-environment/ "environment").

Policy For Minors
-----------------

_We do not knowingly collect data from or market to children under 18 years of age._

We do not knowingly solicit data from or market to children under 18 years of age. By using the Site, you represent that you are at least 18 or that you are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of the Site. If we learn that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, we will deactivate the account and take reasonable measures to promptly delete such data from our records. If you become aware of any data we have collected from children under age 18, please contact us at **contact@facts.net.**

Your **Privacy Rights**
-----------------------

_In some regions, such as the European Economic Area, you have rights that allow you greater access to and control over your personal information. You may review, change, or terminate your account at any time._

In some regions (like the European Economic Area), you have certain rights under applicable data protection laws. These may include the right (i) to request access and obtain a copy of your personal information, (ii) to request rectification or erasure; (iii) to restrict the processing of your personal information; and (iv) if applicable, to data portability. In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information. To make such a request, please use the contact details provided. We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

If we are relying on your consent to process your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note however that this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before its withdrawal.

If you are resident in the European Economic Area and you believe we are unlawfully processing your personal information, you also have the right to complain to your local data protection supervisory authority.

### Cookies and Similar Technologies

Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Site. To opt-out of interest-based advertising by advertisers on our Site, visit this [link](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

California Privacy Rights
-------------------------

_If you are a resident of [California](https://facts.net/california-facts/ "California"), you are granted specific rights regarding access to your personal information._

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in [writing](https://facts.net/lifestyle/17-astonishing-facts-about-writing/ "writing") to us using the contact information provided below.

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with the Site, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Site. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include the email address associated with your account and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Site, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems.

### Mediavine Programmatic Advertising (Ver 1.1)

The Website works with Mediavine to manage third-party interest-based advertising appearing on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use first and third-party cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device (referred to in this policy as a “device”) by the web server so that a website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the Website.

First party cookies are created by the website that you are visiting. A third-party cookie is frequently used in behavioral advertising and analytics and is created by a domain other than the website you are visiting. Third-party cookies, tags, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies (collectively, “Tags”) may be placed on the Website to monitor interaction with advertising content and to [target](https://facts.net/target-facts/ "target") and optimize advertising. Each internet browser has functionality so that you can block both first and third-party cookies and clear your browser’s cache. The “help” feature of the menu bar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to receive notification of new cookies, how to disable existing cookies and how to clear your browser’s cache. For more information about cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information at [All About Cookies](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

Without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of the Website content and features. Please note that rejecting cookies does not mean that you will no longer see ads when you visit our Site. In the event you opt-out, you will still see non-personalized advertisements on the Website.

The Website collects the following data using a cookie when serving personalized ads:

* IP Address
* Operating System type
* Operating System version
* Device Type
* Language of the website
* Web browser type
* Email (in hashed form)

Mediavine Partners (companies listed below with whom Mediavine shares data) may also use this data to link to other end user information the partner has independently collected to deliver targeted advertisements. Mediavine Partners may also separately collect data about end users from other sources, such as advertising IDs or pixels, and link that data to data collected from Mediavine publishers in order to provide interest-based advertising across your online experience, including devices, browsers and apps. This data includes usage data, [cookie information](https://facts.net/cookie-facts/ "cookie information"), device information, information about interactions between users and advertisements and websites, geolocation data, traffic data, and information about a visitor’s referral source to a particular website. Mediavine Partners may also create unique IDs to create audience segments, which are used to provide targeted advertising.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit [National Advertising Initiative opt out page](https://thenai.org/opt-out/). You may also visit [Digital Advertising Alliance website](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/) and [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#) to learn more information about interest-based advertising. You may download the AppChoices app at [Digital Advertising Alliance’s AppChoices app](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) to opt out in connection with mobile apps, or use the platform controls on your mobile device to opt out.

For specific information about Mediavine Partners, the data each collects and their data collection and privacy policies, please visit [Mediavine Partners](https://www.mediavine.com/ad-partners/).

Update To This Policy
---------------------

_We will update this policy as necessary to stay compliant with relevant laws._

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. The updated version will be indicated by an updated “Revised” date and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. We encourage you to review this privacy policy frequently to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

Contact Us
----------

If you have questions or comments about this policy, email us at **contact@facts.net**.

© 2023

Follow us [Subscribe to our channel](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkEWgtngMrn9AcsRTmDgPIQ)
